doing two videos this morning and one
for
each of my channels i started the idea
cafe channel a year ago today
and it hasn't been active in a while
as we've stopped doing idea cafes
because new things have emerged
it's still in existence the channel
itself because both i want the videos to
be there
and it might get used
at some point in the next year or so as
ideas are coming coming out that are
very close to the idea cafe but not the
idea cafe
the reason the idea cafe didn't continue
is
what happened a year ago two days from
now
and i'll do that video then but it won't
be on this channel it'll be on the
jubilee meanders
jubilee create something amazing by me
and drain through life channel
i so a year ago today i did the first
idea cafe it was scheduled on something
to do with teaching and then when i woke
up and realized i had scheduled the very
first one for 9 11
i asked the participants there were
there were three other women who were
going to participate whether they were
okay
switching it to where were you 18 years
ago i.e on 9 11.
and i asking it very specifically in
that way though so if someone didn't
want to mention that story they could
mention something else about their life
at that time
the video quality itself horrible one of
my first times using stream yard
it was choppy i like brought people down
when i really would have loved to see
charlotte mine's um
reaction to miss optimism's story what
happened so anyway so
i had this one of the women say
actually no i'm not okay talking about
that this is a very hard time i'm not a
like basically we shouldn't have the
idea cafe
at all and i was like okay well we're
having the idea cafe this was
whether or not we're gonna change the
topic because it seems worse to kind of
discount what the day is so so the rest
of the people the other person who had
never met before
was like yes let's talk about 9 11. my
friend slash acquaintance who
participated also was okay changing
i was okay with it so i did a bit of an
intro explaining that our stories don't
trump anyone else's
who knows where we were in the world one
of us was in america two of us were
aren't american and were somewhere else
in our own countries when it happened
it was a really cool experience both
because it was just
the idea cafe was like the first
emergence of something that didn't
require
outside technology that i did that was
about having a conversation in the power
of a conversation
and the people that showed up in fact it
happened on 9 11
the fact that these people showed up
that charlotte mine's story were so
parallel to each other even though we've
known each other for
about a decade now and yet we haven't
don't share that story and knowing that
she was
a british person in greece at the time
and not speaking a language whereas i
was a canadian in australia and i spoke
the language
but um like did that difference in
flying in one world not another and then
the third person who showed up
both now that it's a year later and
everything gets unfolded in the last
year
she's recording from her classroom she's
a teacher and i'm like oh god that's
even huge a year later
um she was in new york 20 minute train
ride away from where the towers
collapsed and the story that she tells
during during her experience was huge
the fact that today is
anyway this is the video friday cafe
channel so what i want to
share is just that um that's why that's
why these videos haven't continued on
is i'm continuing doing content on the
other channel as new things emerge i'm
not starting new
channels for them i'm just hosting them
there until they become big enough that
they need their own channel
because since the idea cafe i have tried
citizen assemblies some of the things
have gotten crickets and some of the
things have been more successful
um citizen assemblies we held idea cafes
on communism through game b
we held idea cafes on a bunch of game b
topics as well as the five questions
that have emerged through me
it has been i think the idea cafe is
going to be brought on board with this
new idea that's emerging in me
but the solution raisings came out or
project raisings came out on together
checks
together text channel bentley's idea
and using that same terminology coming
up with solution raising
and and um process raising which was
crickets also didn't quite get the
what what i wanted to get out of it but
i got what i was supposed to get out of
it
and having this whole thing emerge what
has happened in the last year for me
you're not going to know by this channel
because i have 80 subscribers you're not
even know by the other channels because
one has
under 300 subscribers the other one is
50 subscribers but what is happening
behind the scenes we are creating the
technology cooperative
we are creating a way for people to come
together and have conversations that
matter that are important to them
and so the passion idea that sparked
idea cafe is still alive and well
just this channel isn't active because
i'm busy on the other channel
showing my life towards creating a world
that works for everyone
both the project my growth my learning
and
these little days that are rather
eventful
are part of it and i'll explain more
about why this day is even more eventful
in the video i'm doing for the jubilee
create something amazing channel
thank you